espin.com 2007-04-29

# eSPIN-the-Bottle -- Privacy Policy

PRIVACY STATEMENT FOR THE eCRUSH NETWORK®  
_Effective April 29, 2004_

eCRUSH® is committed to protecting your privacy and ensuring that you understand how information about you may be collected and used. This Privacy Policy reviews the information that we collect, how we use that information, who it is shared with, how it is secured and how you can maintain your information.

Please note: by registering for eCRUSH® or by participating in a survey, contest, opt-in program or promotion; or by providing identifiable data, you agree to these terms. As we update and diversify our services this policy will evolve. Please check this page for updates.

This privacy statement covers the sites eCrush.com, eSpin-The-Bottle.com, TruthQuiz.com, Surveys4Teen.com or LookupHookup.com. 

The eCRUSH.com website is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to enable individuals and organizations to establish trusting relationships based on respect for personal identity and information by promoting the use of fair information practices. Because we want to demonstrate our commitment to our users' privacy, we have agreed to disclose our privacy practices and have them reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe.

If users have questions or concerns regarding this statement, please contact support@ecrush.com.

What information does eCRUSH collect?

eCRUSH® collects two kinds of information: anonymous and personally identifiable. Anonymous information is not associated with specific individuals and is used in aggregate to improve the user experience. Personally identifiable information reveals who you are and/or how you can be contacted. It includes your name, address, phone number and email address.

Registration (mandatory to be an eCRUSH® registered user)

To become an eCRUSH® registered user, you need to complete a form with information that may include, but not be limited to, their first and last name, email address, mailing address, telephone number, a user-chosen password, date of birth and other personal information. All users may decline to share such information with us, by simply choosing not to register on the website. All users may opt to remove or correct any such information from our database by contacting us by logging into their account and clicking on the "Update Account" link.

During the registration process, users are given the option to opt-in or out of our mailing (postal and email) lists as well third party promotions. Our own newsletters and promotions are sent by us and contain offers on behalf of advertisers. By not opting out, the user is agreeing to receive current and future offers. For our co-branded offers at registration we obtain your consent to sell or rent the email and/or postal addresses of registered users to bring you great offers directly from our sponsors, partners or advertisers. By checking the boxes the user is agreeing to such use.

Users should contact those third parties directly if they do not wish to receive communications from them, or do not want those third parties to collect information about them. For information on contacting third party advertisers see the How to Opt-out section of this document.

To create a match with their crushes, registered users add their crushes to their eCRUSH® list. Users provide information about this individual which may include the first name, last name, email address, gender and ZIP code of their potential match. We send an email notifying these people that they have been listed with eCRUSH®.

eCRUSH® does NOT do not sell or market the email addresses, or any other personally identifiable information, of any unregistered user (i.e., an individual added to a crush list) to any other third party. This email also contains a link which the recipient can use to block themselves from any future contact from eCRUSH®.

For users who choose to use eSPIN-the-Bottle®

In order to bring people together, we must gather personal information, which may or may not include: customer-specified username, gender, age, ethnic background, appearance, religion, income range, occupation, preference/lifestyle information and general geographic location. Much of this information is optional, and meant to be seen by members and visitors to the site but cannot be used to identify a specific member by name, address, etc.

Public forums (privacy warning)

If you post something that is personally identifiable in a chat room that is offensive or dangerous to yourself or another user, we reserve the right to contact you at the email address you’ve registered with. We also reserve the right to divulge that address to law enforcement or other authorities if necessary

Users should note: any personal information that you disclose on message boards, through email, MatchMail, Notes, Instant Messaging, etc., can be collected and used by anyone, including law-enforcement agencies acting under subpoena power. If you post personal information in public places, others may send you unsolicited email messages. Always be smart about the information you provide online. And, be aware that if eCRUSH® employees find personally identifiable information posted in public areas or within your MatchMail, they will delete it.

How does eCRUSH® use member information?

eCRUSH’s decisions regarding the use of information collected from eCRUSH® members are based on two areas of interest: market research, and improving user experience by offering personalized service, content and advertising.

Ads are a standard part of user experience on the Internet, and eCRUSH® believes that targeted advertising enhances this experience. eCRUSH® uses information collected from eCRUSH® members to place ads where they believe interested parties will see them.

In addition to banner ads, eCRUSH® may advertise products, companies and events that we think might interest you through the email address you provide, if you have elected to receive email from us.

eCRUSH® may analyze information provided by you, obtained through cookies or third parties to direct services and content based on your interests. This is done in the aggregate

eCRUSH® collects market research data in order to generate sales to corporate clients. Market research data are always anonymous Market research data, however, may be used at the aggregate level to:

  1. Improve the likelihood of a sale to a group of eCRUSH® members
  2. Increase the likelihood that a group’s experience on eCRUSH® is relevant to its interests as a whole
  3. Formulate group-level statistical models that are used to accomplish goal #2 (above).

eCRUSH’s market research data is collected in two ways:

  1. Among individuals who opt-in to take surveys during the registration process or while on eCRUSH® (those who sign up are contacted and take surveys through email).
  2. Through surveys that we publicly post on eCRUSH® (it is never mandatory to answer these surveys).

eCRUSH® uses data at the individual level to sell products and services to eCRUSH members who express an interest in these products and services or to members who can be presumed to have an interest based on results from a statistical analysis.

What is eCRUSH’s information retention policy?

To preserve the integrity of our databases, standard procedure calls for us to retain information submitted by members for an indefinite length of time. eCRUSH® understands your submissions as consent to store all your information in one place for this indefinite length of time, if we so wish. We will respond to written member requests to nullify account information. If you wish to make such a request, which requires that we verify your identity, or if you have any questions regarding this policy, contact us directly.

How do we use "Cookies" and "Clickstream" data?

Many companies on the Internet use so-called "cookie" files to track the web surfing habits of their visitors. A "cookie" is a file that the web site places on your computer which contains a unique, randomly assigned number in order to remind the web site of who you are so that the web site can access your registration information and preferences from the web site's computer when you access the web site. Cookies are also used to determine the extent of a users repeat usage, to track "clickstream" data or the trail of web surfing activity you engage in, and to personalize advertising that you may see on the web site.

eCRUSH® may use both session ID and persistent cookie files to customize your experience and to aggregate anonymous click stream data of eCRUSH® users. For example, when a user logs into eCRUSH or eSPIN-the-Bottle, we use a session ID so that user profile preferences are preserved throughout the session. This allows users to go back and forth between parts of the site and have their site preferences stay with them.

However, eCRUSH® will not share with third parties any personally identifiable information collected from such cookies but may share with its business partners anonymous information collected from cookies, as well as demographic information that is not personally identifiable.

Users should also understand that third party advertisers may issue cookies when serving advertisements. We have no control over the use of these cookies once set. Cookies are used extensively in the advertising industry.

If you prefer, you can set your browser to notify you when you have received a cookie or so that your computer will not accept cookies. Some web pages do not function properly where the user's browser is set not to accept cookies.

Pixel tags are tiny graphic files that are included in HTML-encoded e-mail messages. We use pixel tags to gather information about the e-mails we send to our registered users and to recipients of crush messages. When such a message is opened in an HTML-capable e-mail program, the recipient's computer accesses our server to retrieve the pixel tag file, and allows us to record and store the date and time, the recipient's e-mail address, and other standard logging information. The pixel tag also may read cookies.

eCRUSH®’s web pages may also contain similar pixel tags that allow us to count users who have visited those pages, to compile aggregated statistics about site usage, and to deliver co-branded services as they become available. eCRUSH’s pixel tags collect only a limited set of information including a cookie number, time and date of a page view, and a description of the page on which the pixel tag resides. eCRUSH’s pages may also contain pixel tags placed there by third party ad servers, to monitor the effectiveness of their advertising.

What information does eCRUSH® log?

When you surf the Internet, your browser automatically transmits information to the web sites you visit, including eCRUSH. Such information includes referral data (URL of the web page you were on before coming to eCRUSH), IP address and your browser version. eCRUSH® collects this information to help improve services and moderate the site. All the information that is automatically submitted by your browser is considered anonymous by us.

eCRUSH® also logs information you submit through registration, forms for optional programs, surveys and other entries, cookie data and communications transmitted through eCRUSH® applications. Only authorized eCRUSH® staff have access to your information in its entirety. Other employees may have access to bits and pieces of this information if it pertains to their job duties.

How does eCRUSH® secure collected information?

Your eCRUSH® Profile is password-protected so that only you and authorized eCRUSH® employees have access to your account information. In order to maintain this protection, do not give your password to anyone. If anyone ever asks you for information claiming they are eCRUSH® staff, call the office at (773) 384-5131 for verification. Also, if you share a computer, you should sign out of your eCRUSH® account and close the browser window before someone else logs on. This will protect your information on public terminals.

eCRUSH® makes every effort to ensure that your information is secure on its system. Only certain authorized eCRUSH® employees can access this information if it’s relevant to their job duties. eCRUSH® has staff dedicated to maintaining this Privacy Policy and other privacy initiatives, periodically reviewing web security and making sure that every eCRUSH® employee is aware of our security practices. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed 100% secure. As a result, eCRUSH® cannot guarantee the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk.

With whom does eCRUSH® share information?

When you submit information to eCRUSH, it is generally collected, processed and maintained solely by us. Sometimes we send offers to you on behalf of our partners or directly from you via their web site if you have given us consent. When eCRUSH® is the source, it is usually so that we can provide a service with a partner (e.g. when our registration has co-branded options where a user can elect to share their information). We choose to work with upstanding companies that will treat your information responsibly. But, since we don't own these companies, we can't speak for them on privacy issues. Before telling them about you, check out their privacy statements. If you are not satisfied with their information practices, you can choose to not use their service.

Partner Sponsorships

Partners may sponsor promotions, contests and sweepstakes that require you to reveal details such as your name, address or phone number. It will be clear at the point of collection who is collecting the information and whose privacy statement will govern. Always check their privacy policy before revealing information about yourself. If you don’t want these sponsors to have your personal information, you can choose to not participate.

Third Party Service Providers

In order to provide secure online payment options for eCRUSH® Plus subscribers, eCRUSH® has partnered with a company called PayPal. All payment information -- such as credit card or checking account details -- is collected by PayPal on eCRUSH’s behalf. Consequently Paypal is not permitted to use your personal information for any secondary purposes.

Finally, eCRUSH® reserves the right to disclose user information from both private and public areas of the site if required by law or if given reason to believe, in our sole discretion, that someone is causing injury to or interference with the rights of eCRUSH® members or the general public, or with eCRUSH® rights of property.

Collection by Third Parties

eCRUSH® may offer services, contests, sweepstakes, promotions or special offers that are sponsored by or co-sponsored with non-eCRUSH® affiliated companies. Based on our agreement with them, these third parties may obtain personally identifiable information that site visitors voluntarily submit. It will be clear at the point of collection who will be collecting and using the information and consequently whose privacy statement governs that collection. Once submitted, eCRUSH® has no control over the use of this information by these companies.

If you don’t want these sponsors to have your personal information, you can choose to not participate.

When you click on a link or advertisement, you will leave the eCRUSH® web site and arrive at a web site of another party. eCRUSH® does not exercise any control over what third party advertisers do at their web sites after you click through to them and leave our site. Similarly, when you access the eCRUSH® site from another web site, even if that other web site is co-branded with the eCRUSH® brand, the other web site will be controlled by whatever policies are stated on their site.

As mentioned above, for our co-branded offers at registration we obtain your consent to sell or rent the email and/or postal addresses of registered users to bring you great offers directly from our sponsors or partners. By checking the boxes the user is agreeing to such use.

Other Disclosures

We may disclose personally identifiable data pursuant to a subpoena or other judicial or administrative order, where required by law, or, in our sole discretion, where we deem necessary to protect the safety of any individual or the public or to prevent the violation of our Terms of Service Agreement or of the rights of eCRUSH® or any third party.

Tell-A-Friend

If a user elects to use our referral service for informing a friend about our site, we ask them for the friend's name and email address. eCRUSH® will automatically send the friend a one-time email inviting them to visit the site. This information is used for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and is not stored by eCRUSH®. The friend may contact eCRUSH to request the blockage of this information from further unwanted contact.

Children

This web site is designed for participation by those who are 13 years of age or older. CHILDREN UNDER 13 MAY NOT PARTICIPATE.

How to Opt-Out

Our site provides users the opportunity to opt out of receiving our eZine and other communications from us.

Our users are given the opportunity to 'opt-out' of having their information used for purposes not directly related to our site at the point where we ask for information. For example, our order form has an 'opt-out' mechanism so users who register with us, but don't want any marketing material, can keep their email address off of our lists.

Users who no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications may opt-out of receiving these communications by following the instructions at the end of the email. We also offer an opt-out mechanism on each individual member's account page. The user may also contact us at 773-384-5131 to opt-out.

Users of our site are always notified when their information is being collected by any outside parties. We do this so our users can make an informed choice as to whether or not they should proceed with services that require an outside party.

This site gives users the following options for removing their information from our database so as not to receive future communications or no longer receive our service. If you do so, however, you will no longer have access to members-only services.

To Opt-out of correspondence from third party providers, contact that provider directly. If you have questions or concerns about a third party not contained on this list please contact us by phone or email.

Change of Ownership

In the event of a change in ownership, or a direct merger or acquisition with another entity, we reserve the right to transfer all of eCRUSH’s user information, including email and postal addresses, to a separate entity. All registered users will be notified of any change in ownership, merger or acquisition of eCRUSH’s assets by a third party, and may choose to modify any of their registration information at that time.

Revisions to This Policy

eCRUSH® reserves the right to revise, amend, or modify this policy and our other policies and agreements at any time. Notice of any minor revisions, amendments, or modifications will be posted on the website, and a user's continued use of eCRUSH® will signify agreement to such changes. If there are any material changes to this Privacy Policy, eCRUSH® will post a prominent message on our homepage (www.ecrush.com) for 30 days.

International Users

International users, by registering with eCRUSH®, agree that we may collect, use, and transfer user information to servers outside your resident jurisdiction as described in this Privacy Policy. For users residing in the European Union or other jurisdictions that provide access rights under the law, users may access their information or have it corrected or updated in accordance with applicable law, by contacting eCRUSH®.

You can send an e-mail.

You can visit update your User Profile by going to <http://www.ecrush.com/returnuser_login.phtml>

You can contact eCRUSH® by mail at the following postal address:

> Privacy Director  
>  eCRUSH.com®  
>  2035 West Wabansia Ave.  
>  Second Floor  
>  Chicago, Illinois 60647

You can contact eCRUSH® by telephone at the following number: 773-384-5131
